A Guide to the Papers Ellen Glasgow, 1880-1963
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ellen Glasgow 1880-1963
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5060
This collection consists of 3385 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Ellen Glasgow Papers (MSS 5060) was a gift of the estate of Miss Glasgow and was presented to the library on May 7, 1955 by Mrs. Irita Van Doren and Dr. Frank V. Morley of the New York Herald Tribune, 230 West 41st Street, New York, N.Y.
Accession 5083 was a gift of Ms. Anne V. Bennett, 416 West Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, on June 7, 1955.
Accession 6206 was an archival transfer from the files of the Librarian of the University of Virginia Library on January 14, 1960.
Accession 6206-a was a gift of Oliver L. Steele, Jr., 207 Thornton Hall, University of Virginia, on Jan 30, 1962.
Accession 6206-b was an archival transfer from the files of the Rare Book Department, University of Virginia Library, on August 2, 1967.
Accession 6473 was a gift of Ms. Catherine Bent, Editorial Department, Charles Scribner's Sons, 597 Fifth Avenue, New York, N.Y. on Dec 5, 1960.
Accession 7225 was a gift of Mrs. Carrington C. Tutwiler, Brushwood, Lexington, Virginia on July 4, 1963.
Accession 7225-a was a gift of Carrington C. Tutweiler, Jr., P.O. Box 1159, Lexington, Virginia, on September 14, 1966.
Accession 7225-b was a gift of Carrington C. Tutweiler, Jr., through the Rare Book Department, University of Virginia Library, on April 6, 1976 and on October 31, 1977.
Scope and Content
Papers of Ellen Anderson Gholson Glasgow include drafts of and notes on several novels including Phases of an inferior planet, Vein of iron, A certain measure, In this our life, and The woman within, as well as copies of speeches and articles, and notes relating to her personal and literary affairs.
Letters and telegrams, 1916 -1944, from Henry W. Anderson form about half of the correspondence; the more than 50 letters from James Lane Allen make up the second largest group.
The collection also includes notebooks containing addresses, comments, bibliography, recipes and miscellaneous notes; and photographs and drawings of Miss Glasgow, her homes, pets, and other literary figures including a commercial strike of a woodcut of Glasgow's home by J.J. Lankes, 1926, commissioned as a design for her Christmas card.
Container List
- MANUSCRIPTS
  - Short story draft "Between Two Shores", ca. 1898; Ms (Box 1)
  - Rough outline of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - Second draft of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - Final draft of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - Background notes on James River for Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State A of page 1 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 1 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 1 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State D of page 1 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State G of page 1 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 2 (p.3) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 2 (p.3) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 3 (p.4) of Beyond Defeat; see State B of page 2 (p.3), TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 3 (p.4) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State D of page 3 (p.4) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 4 (p.5) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 6 (p.8) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 6 (p.9) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of pages 22-23 (p.24) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 36 (pp.38-39) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 56 (p.55) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 57 (p.68) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State D of page 57 (p.68) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State A of page 58 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - Manuscript and miscellaneous notes for Beyond Defeat, TMs; clipping (Box 1)
  - State A of page 59 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of pages 59 - 60 (p.60-61) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - States B and C of pages 65-66 (p.66) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 73 (p.85) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 75 (p.88) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 84 (p.97) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 78 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 80 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 80 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State D of page 80 of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 88 (p.102) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of pages 99-101 (pp.98-99) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 114 (p.128) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 120 (p.123) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State C of page 122 (p.137) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State D of page 122 (p.137) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of pages 125-129 (pp.127-129) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State D of pages 125-129 (pp.141-144) of Beyond Defeat - see back of p. 143, TMs (Box 1)
  - State F of pages 125-129 (pp.143-144) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State B of page 131 (p.132) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - State G of pages 125-129 (p.144) of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - Uncatalogued pages of Beyond Defeat, TMs (Box 1)
  - Notes for A Certain Measure, n.d.; TMs (Box 2)
  - Page proofs of prefaces from some of Ellen Glasgow's books - collected in preparation for publishing A Certain Measure, n.d.; Page proofs (Box 2)
  - Galley proof - A Certain Measure, n.d.; Galley proof (Box 2)
  - A Creed, n.d.; AMs (Box 2)
  - Drinking Song, n.d.; AMs (Box 2)
  - The Dungeon, n.d.; AMsS, 3 pp. (Box 2)
  - Fate Played A Jest, 2 pp., n.d.; AMs (Box 2)
  - France - 1916, n.d.; TMsS (Box 2)
  - Francisco, n.d.; AMsS (Box 2)
  - Final draft of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 2)
  - Proposed titles for In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Notes for In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Rough draft of preface of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Revised draft of preface of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Final draft of preface, page 1, of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Early draft of page 254 of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Early draft of page 453 of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Early draft of page 465 of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Early draft of pages 473-474 of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Early draft of pages 498-499 of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Early draft of page 241 of In This Our Life, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Book Review of Van Wyck Brooks' An Inadequate Comment on Primary Literature and Coterie-Literature, TMs (Box 3)
  - Draft of Literary Realism or Nominalism: An Imaginary Conversation, n.d.; TMs (Box 3)
  - Draft of A Modern Joan of Arc, short story, [ca. 1900]; AMs (Box 3)
  - Only A Daisy - Ellen Glasgow's first fiction written at age seven, n.d.; AMs (Box 3)
  - Earliest extant draft, pages 1-61, Group I of Phases of an Inferior Planet, n.d.; AMs (Box 3)
  - Earliest extant draft, pages 108-378, Group II of Phases of an Inferior Planet, n.d.; AMs (Box 3)
  - Earliest extant draft, pages 1-240, Phase Second of Phases of an Inferior Planet, AMs (Box 3)
  - Pages 13-17 of Group I, Phases of an Inferior Planet, n.d.; AMs (Box 4)
  - Pages 62-79, Chapter VI, Phase first of Phases of an Inferior Planet, n.d.; AMs (Box 4)
  - Pages 142-152, Chapter XIII, Phase second of Phases of an Inferior Planet, AMs (Box 4)
  - Revision of pages 207-212, Group 2 of Phases of an Inferior Planet, n.d.; AMs (Box 4)
  - Poems: Spirit-Loneliness; A Battle Cry; A Prayer; Remembrance; A Little Lane; France-1916, n.d.; TMsS (7); TMs (6) (Box 4)
  - Draft of The Prairie Flower, short story, ca.1880-1885; AMs (Box 4)
  - A Prayer, n.d.; AMsS (Box 4)
  - Draft of The Professional Instinct, an unpublished story, n.d.; TMs (Box 4)
  - Final draft of The Romantic Comedians, w/autograph corrections, 1925; TMs (Box 4)
  - Page Proofs of The Romantic Comedians, ca. 1926 (Box 4)
  - Galley Proofs of The Romantic Comedians, 1926 (Box 4)
  - Spirit-Loveliness, n.d.; AMsS (Box 5)
  - Notes for They Stooped to Folly, n.d.; TMs (Box 5)
  - To My Dog, n.d.; AMs (Box 5)
  - To Rebe, n.d.; AMsS (Box 5)
  - The Traveller, n.d.; AMsS (Box 5)
  - Notes for Vein of Iron, n.d.; TMs (Box 5)
  - War, n.d.; AMs (Box 5)
  - Essay, What I Believe; two drafts (8 pp. and 19 pp.) and the printed copy in The Nation and several clippings, TMs (Box 5)
  - Woman Suffrage - Expression of opinion w/ printed poem, 1910; AMsS (Box 5)
  - Notebook containing notes for The Woman Within (pp. 229-230, 240-246), also notes on Barren Ground and The Romantic Comedians, AMs (Box 5)
  - The Woman Within - Receipt for manuscript by Frank. V. Morleyand Irita Van Doren, 1946 Feb 15; TMs (Box 5)
  - Two tenative plans for chapter heads and organization of The Woman Within, TMs (Box 5)
  - Author's note on The Woman Within, n.d.; TMs (Box 5)
  - Epilogue: Present Tense for The Woman Within, n.d.; TMs (carbon) (Box 5)
  - First two pages of The Woman Within, n.d.; AMs (Box 5)
  - Notes on The Woman Within, n.d.; AMs (Box 5)
  - First draft, pages 1-254, of The Woman Within, n.d.; TMsS (Box 5)
  - Second draft, pages 1-226, of The Woman Within, TMs (Box 5)
  - Photographs used in The Woman Within, n.d.; Photographs (Box 6)
  - Random Thoughts on the Artist and the Scholar, headed Chapter XIV, rejected chapter for The Woman Within, TMs (Box 6)
  - A Dull Note for Genealogists - a rough draft and carbon copy for The Woman Within, TMs (Box 6)
  - A Dull Note for Genealogists w/notes (The Woman Within), n.d.; TMs (Box 6)
  - Ellen Glasgow to My Literary Executors, 1944 Mar 22; TLS (Box 6)
  - Ellen Glasgow to My Literary Executors, 1945 Jan 6; TL (copy) (Box 6)
  - Ellen Glasgow to My Literary Executors, 1944 Feb 8; TMs (Box 6)
  - Note on Coincidence or Telepathy, commenting on an included letter from Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings(w/ carbon copy), n.d.; TMsS (Box 6)
  - Note by the Literary Executors on Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; TMs (Box 6)
  - Notebooks #1 - #6 with clippings, n.d.; AMs (Box 6)
  - Notebook #7 - #9, n.d.; AMs (Box 7)
  - Notes and clippings removed from unknown notebooks, AMs (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous notes, n.d.; AMs (Box 7)
  - Unidentified notes by Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; TMs (Box 7)
  - Two rough drafts and four printed copies of The Dynamic Past (speech), TMs (Box 7)
  - Political speech w/notes by William W. Kelly and Jonathan Hildreth, ca. 1921; TMs (Box 7)
  - The Reviewer, containing reprint of The Dynamic Past, 1921 Mar 15; 2 TMs (Box 7)
  - Several rough drafts of The Romance of Decay (speech), n.d.; TMs (Box 7)
  - Notes for a speech for Southern Writers, 1931 Oct 23; TMs (Box 7)
  - Are We Maggots, n.d.; 2 TMs (Box 7)
  - Draft of Literary Realism or Nominalism: An Imaginary Conversation, n.d.; TMs (Box 7)
  - The Relation of the Scholar to Creative Art w/notes by J. B. Hubbell, n.d.; 2 TMs (Box 7)
- CORRESPONDENCE
  - Franklin P. Adams to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Aug 5; ALS (Box 8)
  - J. Donald Adams to Ellen Glasgow, 1932-1935; ALS, 23 folders (Box 8)
  - James Lane Allen to Ellen Glasgow, 1910-1923, n.d.; ALS, 52 folders (Box 8)
  - Program, An Evening with James Lane Allen, [ ? ] 21 Apr; Program (Box 8)
  - Receipted account of Ellen Glasgow with C. O. Allen Travel Agency, 1937 Apr 17 (Box 8)
  - American Academy of Arts & Letters & The National Institute of Arts and Letters to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Nov 14; Invitation (Box 8)
  - American Red Cross Missionre Roumania Itinerary, 1917 Jul 17; TL (carbon) (Box 8)
  - American Red Cross (Secretary to Chairman) to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Sep 19; TLS (Box 8)
  - American Shipping to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Jun 21; TLS (Box 8)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Sep 18; Telegram (Box 8)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Jun-Sep; ALS, 14 folders (Box 8)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Sep 29; ALS (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Nov 4; Telegram (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Nov 3; ALS (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Dec 10; Telegram (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1916-1917; TLS, 12 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Aug 20; APCS (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 May-Jul; TLS, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917; Telegrams, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Jul 18; ALS (Box 9)
  - Note (fragment) by Ellen Glasgow, 1917 July 19 (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Jul 26-28; 2 Telegrams (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Jul 31; ALS (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Aug 1-2; 2 Telegrams (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Aug 3-20; ALS, 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917; ALS, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Aug 29; APCS (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Sep-Nov; TLS, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Nov 27; Telegram (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917 Dec 10; ALS (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1917-1918; Telegram (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1918 May-Jun; 4 Telegrams, 2 folder (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1918 Jul-Aug; ALS, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1918 Nov-Dec; ALS, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1919 Jan-Jul; ALS, 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1919 Oct-Nov; Telegram, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1919 Dec; ALS (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Andersonpapers, 1919-1925, n.d.; ALS (Box 9)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Jan; Telegram (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Apr-Aug; ALS, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1920; ALS & Telegram (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1920 Oct; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1920; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1921; ALS & Telegram (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 Mar; Telegram (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 May; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 Aug; Telegram (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1921 Sep; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgowre Republican slate for Virginia offices, 1921 Nov; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1922 Jun-Dec; ALS, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1922-1923; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1923 Jan-Dec; ALS, 10 folders (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1924 Apr-Dec; ALS, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1925 Jan-Dec; ALS, 12 folders (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1925; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Jan-Mar; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 May; ALS; Telegram (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Jun-Dec; ALS, 6 folders (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1926; ALS (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgowand House of Flowers to Henry W. Anderson, 1927 June; ALS; Telegram (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1927 Jul, Dec; ALS, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1928 Jan; ALS (Box 11)
  - Frances Newmanto Ellen Glasgow, 1928 Apr 4; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Apr-Dec; ALS, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1929; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Mar-Aug; ALS, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Jun; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Jan-Aug; ALS, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1933-5; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 Oct-Dec; ALS, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Feb 16; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Apr-Dec; ALS, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1937-9; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Mar-Jun; ALS, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Oct-Dec; ALS, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ca. 1939-1945; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jan-Jun; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Apr; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 5; Telegram (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Jun-Aug; ALS, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Feb-Oct; ALS, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Oct 27; ALS (Box 11)
  - Henry W. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, ALS (Box 11)
  - Laura E. Anderson to Ellen Glasgow, 1918 Nov 19; ALS (Box 11)
  - James R. Angell to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Jun 5; TLS (Box 11)
  - James R. Angell to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Oct 30; TLS (Box 11)
  - Georges Assie to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 Oct 12; ALS (Box 11)
  - Gertrude Franklin (Horn) Atherton to Ellen Glasgow, [ ? ] Jul 5; ALS (Box 11)
  - Thomas Parker Ayer to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Apr 3; TLS (Box 11)
  - Dr. Pearce Bailey to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Mar 2, 8; ALS (Box 11)
  - Stringfellow Barr to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Mar 23; TLS (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Basso to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 Nov 7; TLS (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Basso to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Oct 1; ALS (Box 11)
  - Hamilton Basso to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Nov 19; ALS (Box 11)
  - Mary R. Beard to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 May 6; TLS (Box 11)
  - Mary R. Beard to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 May 15; TLS w/autograph note (Box 11)
  - May B. (Lamberton) Becker to Ellen Glasgow, 1934 Jun 20; ALS (Box 11)
  - Thomas Beer to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Aug 2; ALS (Box 11)
  - John Howard Beel to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Feb 5; ALS (Box 11)
  - Rosemary Benet and Stephen Vincent Benet to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 5; Telegram (Box 11)
  - Stephen Vincent Benet to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 May 3; TLS (Box 11)
  - Arnold Bennett to Ellen Glasgow, 1916 Apr 14; ALS (Box 11)
  - Laurence Bliss to Ellen Glasgow, 1909 Jan 25; ALS (Box 12)
  - Dr. James Bordley, Jr. to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 Sep 14; TLS (Box 12)
  - Robert Boswell to Ellen Glasgow w/encl., 1931 Jan 22; ALS (Box 12)
  - R. W. Boatwright to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Feb 4; TLS (Box 12)
  - Warren Bower to Stark Young, 1935 Sep 20; TLS (Box 12)
  - Donald Brace to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 6; TLS (Box 12)
  - Arthur Granville Bradley to Mrs. Gholson, 1926 Oct 2; ALS (Box 12)
  - Herschel Brickell to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Aug 11, 25; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - J. Fulmer Bright to Ellen Glasgow, 1928 May 21; TLS (Box 12)
  - Eleanor Stimson Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Apr 26; ALS (Box 12)
  - Eleanor Stimson Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jan 7; ALS (Box 12)
  - Eleanor Stimson Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Jul-Oct; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Eleanor Stimson Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; ALS (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Oct-Nov; ALS, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Feb-May; ALS, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Jul-Nov; ALS, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jan; ALS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Apr 14; ALS (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jun 14; TLS (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jul 7,14; ALS, TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Aug 26; ALS (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Oct-Dec; ALS, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Jan 18; ALS (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Feb-Oct; ALS, TLS (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to Ellen Glasgow, n.d.; ALS (copy) (Box 12)
  - Van Wyck Brooks to [Ellen Glasgow], n.d.; ALS (Box 12)
  - Lucy Brown to Ellen Glasgow, 1909 Dec 21; ALS (Box 12)
  - Thalia Newton Brown to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Dec 16; TLS (Box 12)
  - William Cabell Bruce to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Apr 24; TLS (Box 12)
  - Ella Howard Bryanto Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Sep 20; TLS (Box 12)
  - John Stewart Bryanto Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Jan 9; ALS (Box 12)
  - John Stewart Bryanto Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Mar 8; TLS (Box 12)
  - John Stewart Bryan to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Jan 7; ALS (Box 12)
  - Page Bryan to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 May 5; Telegram (Box 12)
  - Nicholas Murray Butler to Ellen Glasgow re election to American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1939 Feb 10; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1923 Nov 5; ALS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1924 Oct-Nov; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1926 Sep 26; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1927 Oct 14; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1928 Sep; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Jul; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1929 Sep 9; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Jan-Feb; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1930 Apr-Jun; TLS, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1931 Jul 6; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1932 Aug-Sep; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1933 May 5; TLS w/encl. (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1935 Jul-Aug; TLS, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1936 Feb-Oct; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1937 Sep 16; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Feb; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Jul; TLS, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Aug 12; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Oct 16; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1938 Dec 26; TLS (Box 12)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Aug 16; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Sep 4; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1939 Nov 22; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jan; TLS, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 May 5; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Jul 15; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1940 Aug-Sep; TLS, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Jan-Feb; TLS, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Jul-Aug; TLS, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1941 Dec 18; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Jan; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Jul 9; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1942 Dec 20; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Jan 28; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 May 31; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Jul 4; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Sep; TLS, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Oct 6; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1943 Dec 11; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Jun 25; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Nov 23; TLS (Box 13)
  - James Branch Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Aug 30; TLS (Box 13)
  - Priscilla Cabell to Ellen Glasgow, 1944 Nov 26; ALS w/encl. (Box 13)